Guide to the Alix Kates Shulman Papers, 1892-2014, bulk 1968-2014 RL.01183
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Restricted Series
  - Restricted Materials Category 1
    - Books Subseries (Box RM2)
      - Awake or Asleep, (use copy of manuscript) [ca. 1969] (Box RM2)
      - Bosley on the Number Line, [ca. 1970], 6 folders (Box RM2)
      - Burning Questions, manuscript, 4 folders (Box RM2)
      - Burning Questions, speeches/promotions (Box RM2)
      - Cleveland Book, 3 folders (Box RM2)
      - Drinking the Rain, manuscript and notes, folders 1-18 of 23 (Box RM3)
      - Drinking the Rain, manuscript and notes, folders 19-23 of 23 (Box RM4)
      - Emma Goldman, [ca. 1970], folders 1-11 of 13 (Box RM4)
      - Emma Goldman, [ca. 1970], folders 12-13 of 13 (Box RM5)
      - Finders Keepers, [ca. 1970] (Box RM5)
      - In Every Woman's Life, manuscript and notes, folders 1-13 of 14 (Box RM5)
      - In Every Woman's Life, manuscript, folder 14 of 14 (Box RM6)
      - Memoirs of an Ex-Prom Queen, manuscript, notes, research, and screenplay, folders 1-16 of 18 (Box RM6)
      - Memoirs of an Ex-Prom Queen, manuscript, notes, research, and screenplay, folders 17-18 of 18 (Box RM7)
      - On the Stroll, manuscript, 4 folders (Box RM7)
    - Academic Work Series
      - Grant application materials, 1974-1985 (Box RM7)
    - Public Speaking Series
      - Speeches
        - Emma Goldman speech, 1981 (Box RM7)
  - Restricted Materials Category 2
    - Personal Papers Series (Box RM8)
      - Biographical
        - Address book (Box RM8)
    - Literary Work Series
      - Royalty statements and bank contracts, 2 folders (Box RM8)
  - Restricted Materials Category 3
    - Closed correspondence (Box RM9)
- Oversize Materials Series, 1949-1996
  The Oversize Materials Series, 1949-1995 and undated, contains miscellaneous materials, including a photograph of Shulman and others in her sorority at Cleveland Heights High School and large magazines featuring Shulman. Materials within each series are arranged alphabetically.
  - Political Work Series, 1967-2000
    - China Pictorial magazine, 1975 (Oversize-box 1)
    - China Reconstructs magazine, June 1977 (Oversize-box 1)
  - Personal Papers Series, 1892-2000
    - Calendars, 1985, 1988 (Oversize-box 1)
    - Finders Keepers, undated (Oversize-box 1)
    - Sorority photograph 1949 (Oversize-box 1)
  - Public Speaking Series, 1972-2000
    - Life magazine, April 28, 1972 (Oversize-box 1)
    - The New York Times, The Living Section, May 31, 1995 (Oversize-box 1)
    - The New York Times Magazine, April 15, 1990 (Oversize-box 1)
    - Voice Literary Supplement, October, 1993 (Oversize-box 1)
- Accession (2000-0391), 1975-1998; 3 boxes
  Scope and Contents
  This accession consists mainly of calendars and datebooks, but also includes documentation of book promotion tours, foreign travel itineraries, records of expenses, and correspondence.
  - Correspondence (4 folders), 1998 (Box 1)
  - Foreign travel itineraries (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Appointment books, calendars, 1975-1980 (Box 1)
  - Appointment books/calendars, 1982-1995 (Box 2)
  - Appointment book/calendar, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Appointment book/calendar, 1985, 1988 (Box Ovsz. box 133)
- Accession (2004-033), [1960s]-2003 (bulk 2000-2003); 1 boxes
  Material documenting Shulman's activism and writing, including reviews, book-tour itineraries, promotional materials, and information related to speaking engagements. Also includes a few pieces of ephemera from the women's liberation movement of the 1960s and 1970s, including cards to be distributed to ""cat-callers"" and stickers reading ""This is Insulting to Women.""
- Accession (2005-0117), 1987-2005; 2 boxes
  Correspondence, subject files pertaining to the Women Writing Women's Lives seminar, Woman2000, National Writers Union, Vermont Studio Center, and PEN America Center, and clippings.
- Accession (2014-0176), 1971-2014; 4 boxes
  Includes correspondence, including Naomi Weisstein and Oliver Sachs, speeches, writings by Alix Kates Shulman (appearances in anthologies, magazines, journals, newspapers, and book manuscripts), as well as reviews, calendars, research and activist files, and writings by others.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Labeled and stamped folder: Book proposal for "The Visionaries" in 2014/0176 Box 4 closed until the book is published or Alix Kates Shulman's death, whichever comes first.
  - Periodicals - 2008-2013 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (4 folders), 1984-2013 (Box 1)
  - Could Happen: A Memoir of Love Under Pressure (Box 1)
  - Pub Sources, Lit Bas, Lists TLWI - 2008-2009 (Box 1)
  - AK Notes for Scott Book - 2005-2006 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence with Oliver Sacks re Scott & To Love What Is - 2007-2008 (Box 1)
  - Memoir - 2008-2013 (Box 1)
  - To Love What Is: Reviews, Etc., (2 folders), 1996-2009 (Box 1)
  - Scott Memoir Readings & Clips & Research - 2005-2008 (Box 1)
  - Readers of Scott Book - 2006-2008 (Box 1)
  - Emails re Scott's Fall - 2004-2005 (Box 1)
  - To Love What Is Manuscript - December 21, 2006 (Box 1)
  - To Love What Is Manuscript - December 15, 2007 (Box 1)
  - The Accident (Could Happen) (To Love What Is) Manuscript - January 12, 2007 (Box 1)
  - To Love What Is Manuscript 1 of 2 (Ch 1-4) - November 20, 2007 (Box 1)
  - To Love What Is Manuscript 2 of 2 (Ch 5-9) - November 20, 2007 (Box 1)
  - The Accident (To Love What Is) Manuscript - January 9, 2007 (Box 1)
  - The Accident (To Love What Is) Manuscript, 1 of 2 (Ch 1-4) - December 21, 2006 (Box 1)
  - The Accident (To Love What Is) Manuscript, 2 of 2 (Ch 5-9) - December 21, 2006 (Box 1)
  - To Love What Is Manuscript, 1 of 2 (Ch 1-4) - April 15, 2008 (Box 1)
  - To Love What Is Manuscript, 2 of 2 (Ch 5-9) - April 15, 2008 (Box 1)
  - First Pass To Love What Is (2 folders) - 2008 (Box 2)
  - The Gallatin Review: Thirtieth Anniversary Issue - May 1, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Caprice - 1989 (Box 2)
  - Dissent (A Marriage Disagreement) - Winter 1998 (Box 2)
  - Global City Review (Sexual Politics Issue) - Spring 1993 (Box 2)
  - N + 1 - Winter 2013 (Box 2)
  - Journal of Aging, Humanities, and the Arts, v. 2, nos. 3-4, July-December 2008 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence (2 folders) - 2006-2014 (Box 2)
  - Charitable Donations - 2002-2003 (Box 2)
  - Calendars, 2001-2005 (Box 2)
  - Cards from Scott's Hospitalization in Maine - 2004 (Box 2)
  - Traumatic Brain Injury Survival Guide - 2004-2005 (Box 2)
  - Scott's Rehab Calendar - 2004 (Box 2)
  - Undated Photos of Alix - Undated (Box 2)
  - Periodicals - 1971-2012 (Box 2)
  - San Francisco - November 11, 2003-November 21, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence with Scott's Children - 2007-2011 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous: Personal, Activist, Political, Biographical Activities (2 folders) - 1994-2013 (Box 2)
  - Memoirs of an Ex Prom Queen Screenplay - April 27, 2006 (Box 3)
  - Memoirs of an Ex Prom Queen Screenplay - March 16, 2005 (Box 3)
  - Enthusiasm: Typescript by Alix's Daughter Polly Shulman (2 folders) - Undated (Box 3)
  - Occupy Movement, Women Occupy Wall Street, & Feminist Assemblies - 2012 (Box 3)
  - Talks by Alix Kates-Shulman - 2007-2014 (Box 3)
  - Memoirs of an Ex Prom Queen Legal Docs - 2002-2003 (Box 3)
  - Menage Reviews, Ads, Etc. - 2012 (Box 3)
  - RPS - 2011-2012 (Box 3)
  - Marriage & Feminism - 1991-2008 (Box 3)
  - Opportunity Knocks (3 folders) - Undated (Box 3)
  - Opportunity Knocks Manuscript: Early, before Scott's fall (2 folders) - Undated (Box 3)
  - Opportunity Knocks! Manuscript (2 folders) - Undated (Box 3)
  - Book Appearances - 1995-2000 (Box 3)
  - A Marriage Agreement and Other Provocations - 1998-2012 (Box 3)
  - Papers re: A Good Enough Daughter - 1999 (Box 3)
  - A Good Enough Daughter (a memoir) Manuscript (3 folders) - 1997 (Box 3)
  - Book Proposal: The Visionaries - Undated (Box 3)
    Labeled, stamped, and tied folder: Book proposal for "The Visionaries" closed until the book is published or Alix Kates Shulman's death, whichever comes first.
  - Miscellaneous Speaking Engagement Advertisements - 2000-2013 (Box 4)
  - The New York Review of Books 1993 by David Levine Calendar - 1993-94, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Women's Review of Books: Volume 31, Issue 2 - March/April 2014 (Box 4)